Welcome to Renegade Immortal, this donghua is an adaptation of the eponymous web novel written by Er Gen. \NIn these subtitles, I will assume the viewer doesn't have any prior knowledge of the genre of cultivation. Please read the attached README and always check for notes at the end of the episodes.\NThank you for watching Bonobosubs, I hope you will enjoy this awesome show !
Thousands of years ago,
the Heaven Defying Bead, an ancient artifact
fell into the cultivation world.
The strongest individual in the country of Suzaku, Situ Nan, obtained it.
The rumor is that
the Heaven Defying Bead is the key to the Ancient Celestial Realm.
Since then,
the battle for this artifact never stopped.
Four Symbols Mountain\NPlanet Suzaku
Heaven Defying Bead
The bead is mine !
Situ, the Heaven Defying Bead is not something you can hold.
Shut up.
Situ Nan\NSecond generation Suzaku\NPeak Ascendant
If you can have it
then why can't I ?
How presumptuous...
To think I, the strongest individual on planet Suzaku,
the second generation Suzaku,
would be strong enough to need outsiders to join hands in defeating me.
This life was worth it !
Hand over the Heaven Defying Bead and I'll spare your life.
And if I... refuse !?
Now die !
The Death Finger ?
As time goes on,
The Heaven Defying Bead !
fate will turn in my favor.
Accept your fate and stay mortal
or defy it to become immortal !
Note: This is an ancient confucian text.
When the heavens are about bestow a great responsibility on a man,
they first test his resolve,
exhaust his body,
starve him,
empty his being,
and thwart all his efforts.
Wang Lin\NWang Family
Only by cultivating patience and perseverance
can one overcome everything.
Wang Lin's house\NWang Family Village
Zhou Yingsu\NWang Lin's mother
Wang Tianshui\NWang Lin's father
Note: Tie Zhu is Wang Lin's nickname.
Tie Zhu,
the village has to gift wood carvings of Immortals
at the Immortal Assembly in 3 days.
This is a once-in-three-years opportunity
to influence the protection the Immortals provide to our country of Zhao.
They must have
outstanding form and spirit.
Dear, Tie Zhu,
lunch is ready.
Okay, you can start without me.
Wang Family members
You again !
Second Brother, have you been keeping up with the interest this month ?
Let's check over there.
What kind of junk is this ?
This much is barely acceptable...
We will pay back everything we owe.
But this money was saved up for Tie Zhu's imperial exam.
Shut up and move !
It's our family's lifeline,
you can't take it !
Get lost !
Debts must be paid.
If you can't even repay your family
then what future do you have ?
You can take whatever you want from us,
but this money is my son's future !
I'm begging you !
Father, Mother,
get up !
You won't earn your son a future by kneeling !
Oh...
At least Tie Zhu understands.
You'd better get ready for next month.
Let's go !
Sigh...
How could the Wang Family
not tolerate me, their second bastard son ?
Debts must be paid,
they're right...
But who should I turn to
in order to clear my debts ?
Tie Zhu,
you can probably take
next year's imperial exam.
We've failed you...
Let's prepare for another year,
it's fine.
Tie Zhu has grown up !
Fourth Uncle !
Wang Tiantu\NWang Lin's Fourth Uncle
Fourth Brother, you came !
Brother, sit down.
I came as fast as I could,
but I was too late !
These people are getting more outrageous !
I came today
for something important.
The Heng Yue Sect, a major Immortal sect in Zhao
is recruiting disciples.
They have given
3 spots to our Wang Family.
I fought hard
to get Tie Zhu a chance to participate.
If Tie Zhu joins an Immortal sect,
those guys won't dare to bully you again.
Immortal cultivation sounds great,
but I have heard it's an incredibly dangerous path.
We will make more carvings this year
so he can focus on next year's imperial exam.
As for the debts, even if it takes decades,
I will pay them back.
Even if it takes 20 years,
I accept it.
Father,
Mother,
I've never slacked off all these years
but our family still suffers.
I won't let you be oppressed anymore.
I won't let you work so hard.
I've made up my mind.
If life is already hard,
I might as well risk it all.
Our fate isn't set by the heavens !
Tie Zhu...
Brother, Sister,
at least let Tie Zhu try.
Father, Mother,
Fourth Uncle...
Tie Zhu won’t disappoint you.
Since I’ve chosen the hardest path,
I’ll give it my all !
Back then, when we were kicked out of the village,
I never thought we’d return one day.
Tie Zhu,
don’t take their harsh words to heart.
Father, don’t worry.
Wang Family Ancestral Hall
Wang Family Ancestral Hall\NWang Family Village
Oh,
it's Second Brother and Tie Zhu.
Please forgive us for earlier.
Tie Zhu has come !
Tie Zhu has been clever since childhood.
Exactly !
Wang Hao\NWang Lin's cousin
Brother Tie Zhu, you’re here !
Yes.
The Immortals take disciples
based on whether they are fated.
Wang Zhuo\NWang Lin's cousin
Do you think that carving wood Immortals
will help you absorb spiritual energy ?
I have heard
that Immortal Xu of the Heng Yue Sect took a liking to Wang Zhuo.
That’s why our Wang Family got 3 spots.
Is that an Immortal !?
It really is an Immortal !
The Immortal has come !
Greetings Immortal !
So this is an Immortal ?
Are you three
the candidates ?
Zhang Kuang\NHeng Yue Sect disciple\N8th layer of Qi Condensation
Greetings Immortal,
these are the three.
Are you Wang Zhuo ?
You are a fine young man.
No wonder Uncle Daoxu took a liking to you.
You flatter me, Senior Brother.
I am Wang Lin.
I am Wang Hao.
Hop on.
Immortal,
allow me to bid farewell to my parents.
Father,
Mother,
your son will do his best.
Please take care of yourselves.
My son, it doesn't matter if you are not chosen.
You can always come back, we will always be there for you.
Mother, don’t worry.
Country bumpkins...
Brother Tie Zhu, don’t worry,
I’ll look out for you at the Heng Yue Sect.
Okay,
I’ll count on you then.
Heng Yue Sect\NCountry of Zhao
Wow...
Is this an Immortal sect ?
Immortal Platform\NHeng Yue Sect
Why is the fog so thick ?
Immortal sects
really are mysterious.
Ignorants.
This is the Fog Concealment Formation,
did you think mortals can just stumble upon the sect ?
Huanglong Zhenren\NHeng Yue Sect Leader\NPeak Late stage Foundation Establishment
I am Huanglong Zhenren,
the Heng Yue Sect Leader.
The Heng Yue Sect’s disciple selection has always been strict.
Among all of you,
only a few will be chosen
to be Heng Yue Sect disciples.
Talent is primordial for cultivation.
The first test is: Spirit Roots
Sun Dazhu\NHeng Yue Sect Elder\NEarly stage Foundation Establishment
Daoxu Zhenren\NHeng Yue Sect Elder\NEarly stage Foundation Establishment
Not qualified.
You must be Wang Zhuo, whom Junior Brother Daoxu mentioned.
You indeed have some talent.
Stand to the right.
Not qualified.
Look at this guy.
It'll soon be my turn...
Immortal, I bless you to live a long life.
Your humble servant Wang Hao kowtows to you.
You might be clever
but your talent is...
Immortal,
this is a 300 years old spirit herb my father found in the mountains.
I brought it specially for you
as a gift.
It happens that I'm in need of a helper for alchemy.
Are you willing to be my helper ?
Disciple is willing !
You can do this ?!
Not qualified.
If you can't even repay your family, then what future do you have ?
You can take whatever you want from us, but this money is my son's future !
Do you think that carving wood Immortals
will help you absorb spiritual energy ?
The first test is:
Spirit Roots
No, it's not over yet.
This Zhenren guy said this is was only the first test.
It means
there must be others tests.
Spirit Roots are important for cultivation
but those with enough perseverance
may also become sect disciples.
Whether you can join the Heng Yue Sect
will depend on whether you can climb these steps.
Heavenly Steps\NHeng Yue Sect
If you can reach the summit before the sunset.
then you will pass.
If you can't, then you will fail.
If you feel like you can't endure it anymore,
then shout “I give up”
and someone will retrieve you.
I was first !
Stop pushing me !
Get out of my way !
Why are you pushing ?!
This is my last chance.
Move !
What’s happening ?
Where’s is this fire coming from ?
I give up !
I’m burning !
Eliminated.
I can’t hold on !
I give up !
Eliminated.
This is…
an illusion ?
It's all in my head.
It's all in my head...
Even if it were real
and I end up crippled,
I’ll still climb to the top !
Immortal Pavilion\Nof the Sacred Mountain\NHeng Yue Sect
You must persevere
I must persevere...
I want to become an Immortal !
What’s this ?
I can see the end of the test.
Why are you rejecting me !?
Time is up.
This boy really is perseverant
but the Dao is merciless.
It's futile,
it really is futile...
Finally...
This day has arrived !
Thank you for watching this first episode. I will often put notes at the end of episodes to explain cultivation concepts and to detail things that might not have been adapted correctly.\N\NFirst, what is the Dao ? It's the metaphysical representation of everything in Daoism. Everything is the Dao and the Dao is everything, it's the fundamental force of the world. In a cultivation context the Dao will be used in this meaning but also used with the meaning of a path. "The Dao of alchemy" for example is the path of alchemy, the truth of alchemy, someone's understanding of what the essence of alchemy is. Pursuing the Dao is trying to understand the heavens and the earth.\N\NA common concept is "Tian Dao", the Dao of the heavens. I will be referring to it as "the law of the heavens" for simplicity's sake but you can have the double interpretation of it thanks to the understanding of what Dao means.\N\NSecond, you were introduced to cultivation levels in the character cards of this episode, the concept of what cultivation is will be further explained in the next episode so don't worry about it for now. By the way, don't hesitate to pause to read character cards.\N\NThird, you were introduced to the concept of formations with the "Fog Concealment Formation", think of formations as spells that use something as a proxy. A mountain can be used as a formation to create fog or create a barrier for example. A formation can be engraved in a plate or a stone platform, can be quickly created by planting flags in the ground, a group of people can be used as a formation, etc... You will have the occasion of seeing many formations in this story.
I've been walking this path for endless years
just to catch a glimpse of your silhouette.
Is it the compass of fate
that wrote this outcome for us ?
The heavens want to erase your existence,
that's the obsession guiding me.
Is this the path to uncover
truths from falsehoods ?
In a world of murk and shadow,
only the flame of truth can light the way.
Look at them all,
being carried by the waves.
being drowned.
I don't want to believe in whoever decides fate,
I will let the world refine my soul.
So what if I become an Immortal and defy the heavens ?
I will fight.
I'll break through the abyss of despair
to finally learn who I really am.
My body is stained by the bloody color of slaughter,
I embrace this obsession.
I won't glance back at the wasteland I left behind.
Even if this suffering shatters my soul
and I'm reborn countless times in hell,
I'll still fight.
It's hard to avoid loneliness
when you are above everyone else.
Can a moth that has witnessed the flames of a Suzaku
be afraid of a firefly ?